Ben Burke

Profile

A dynamic and driven individual with a passion for engineering and technology. Holds a degree in Computer Systems Engineering from the University of Kent and practical experience in electronics, circuit design, programming, and robotics. Awarded several academic achievements including the IET Award for distinction and the School of Engineering Industrial Placement Award. A quick learner with strong problem-solving skills and team-oriented mindset.

Education

Bedford College, 2016 - 2018

Electrical and Electronic Engineering, Level 3
Distinction* Distinction

University of Kent, Canterbury, 2018-2022

Bachelor of Engineering with Honours Computer Systems Engineering with Year-in-Industry First Class

University of Kent – Systems-focused bachelor's degree incorporating electronic engineering and computer science modules. Key areas explored include fundamentals of electronics and circuit design, digital and analogue systems and mathematical systems modelling, and signal processing. A range of languages are covered, including MATLAB, C/C++, VHDL, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, and SQL. Included a year-in-industry between the second and third stages.

Bedford College – Two-year A-Level-equivalent course covering core introductory areas of electrical and electronic engineering. Units covered core and further mathematics, electrical principles, circuit design and build with both theoretical and practical experience. The second year had a large focus on microcontrollers, microprocessors and programming in C++ and Assembly.

Skills

Programming Experience and Languages

Java, Object Oriented Programming

Python

JavaScript / TypeScript

C, C++

Linux, Bash

Powershell

Microcontrollers (C++ and Assembly) (register level and real-time)

FPGA Programming (VHDL)

Front End Web Development – HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular, Electron,

Back End Web Development - REST, NodeJS, Express, Flask, SQL

Computer Aided Design and Manufacturing

3D Modelling, Fusion 360

3D Printing, FDM and SLA

Experience

- o **Final Year Dissertation Project, 2021-2022** Development of a robotic prosthetic hand and complementary camera-based control system. Novel ground-up design of 3D-printed, mechanically self-contained robotic prosthetic hand. Custom-designed electronics control circuitry using ESP32 microcontroller, running custom-made program implementing FreeRTOS for multitasking. Complementary camera-based hand tracking system created, combining AI models with forward and inverse kinematics to generate control patterns for the developed prosthetic hand.
- o CGI Year-in-Industry, 2020-2021 Between the second and third stages of study in my bachelor's degree, a year spent in CGI's Space, Defence and Intelligence Business Unit working on a Cybersecurity project as a software engineer. Worked in a team which followed Agile development through SCRUM. Hands-on experience with a large-scale cybersecurity solution at the hardware and software side, spending the year in the deployment team managing releases and addressing system bugs.
- o **Rotary Youth Leadership Awards, 2018** Attended the 2018 RYLA program, sponsored by Rotarians from East Anglia, focused on leadership and team building through various physical and mental challenges such as outdoor activities, a business simulation game, and a two-day expedition. The program was intense and designed to push participants to their limits.
- o **Cranfield Precision (Fives Landis), 2018** Two days at bespoke CNC Machine design and build firm. Shadowed highly experienced electronics lead design engineer in the electronics design and build wing of the site. Completed a PIC programming dice-roll project in Assembly Language.
- o **Mercedes-AMG High Performance Powertrains, 2017** Five-day work experience at the Mercedes AMG Formula 1 Engineering Center, learning about their high-performance powertrain through hands-on experience in various teams and learning about engineering workflows, parts inspection, and the use of quality assurance machinery.

Key Achievements

Institution of Engineering and Technology (IET) Award, University of Kent, 2022

Awarded for distinction shown at the University of Kent in a course leading to the award of a degree in Computer Systems Engineering.

The School of Engineering Industrial Placement Award, University of Kent, 2022

Awarded for best performance in the industrial placement year final report at the University of Kent.

Rapid Electronics Sponsored Best Project Demonstration Award, University of Kent, 2020

Awarded joint first place for best project demonstration for in 2nd year of bachelor's degree for group project module.

Rapid Electronics Sponsored Cross-Channel Robotics Competition, University of Kent, 2019

Awarded for demonstrating notable performance in inter-university robotics project in first year of bachelor's degree, sponsored by Rapid Electronics.

Mercedes-AMG Sponsored Engineering Student of the Year, Bedford College, 2017

Presented the Mercedes-AMG Sponsored for notable dedication to engineering in first year of course.